Wen-Yu (Marty) Cheng

www.linkedin.com/in/wen-yu-cheng | martywycheng.github.io | marty.chengwy@gmail.com | (561) 809-4593

Summary

Versatile researcher with over 7 years of experience in smart wearables design, Al integration, robotics, rapid prototyping, cross-domain problem solving, academic/grant writing, and leadership. Loves solving critical challenges. Possess deep expertise across multiple engineering fields for interdisciplinary projects. Highly interested in Al applications in medical and Human-Computer/Human-Robot Interaction (HCI/HRI) fields.

Experience

Research Assistant

08/2018 - Present Boca Raton, FL

Florida Atlantic University, BioRobotics Lab, Dr. Erik Engeberg

- Designed a novel high-density **Force Myogram (FMG)** sensor array, outperforming EMG with 99% classification accuracy across 20 hand gestures using AI pattern recognition in a test involving **over 10 human subjects**. Publication currently in progress.
- Developed and integrated custom software, firmware, and hardware components for data collection, featuring a novel **biodata** processing and analysis method with an intuitive subject testing **user interface**.
- Led the development of a Variable-Pressure **Prosthetic Socket** using Granular Jamming technology and secured **\$1,200** in 2021 to further advance the project.
- Led a project team in securing \$2,400 in consecutive grants (2018 and 2019) to develop a novel modular Soft Robotic Haptic Feedback system.

Florida Atlantic University, Dr. Zhen Ni

- Developed a low-cost Wireless Charging Station for use with the integrated **computer vision** system of the TurtleBot 3 mobile robot platform. Results published and presented at **2023 IEEE HONET** conference.
- Improved an Al PPO training algorithm for Kinova Gen 3 manipulator parallel training. Publication in progress.

Research Intern

Johns Hopkins University, Dr. Nitish Thakor

06/2020 - 02/2024 Baltimore, MD

- Designed a novel biomimetic Soft-Rigid Hybrid Prosthetic Finger with more than 3 times the grasping force of traditional soft robotic prosthetic fingers. Published findings in IEEE Science Advances Journal.
- Performed extensive finite element analysis (FEA) to ensure proper material selection and prevent failure.
- Integrated an innovative tactile sensor into the hybrid prosthetic finger for biomimetic **touch sensing**. Published findings at the 2022 **IEEE Sensors** Conference.

Systems Engineer Golden Hour Medical

11/2023 – 03/2024 Boca Raton, FL

- Led the effort in bringing new **IoT-enabled** life-saving **automatic tourniquet** device into mass production and ensured functionality of critical complex systems, all within **four months** of the fast-moving demands of a new **startup**.
- Operated with strict adherence to FDA **ISO 13485** and **14971** regulations for biomedical devices, including extensive engineering documentation/history and collaborating with the Quality Assurance team for device risk management.

Skills

- Design/Prototyping Solidworks, Fusion 360, Blender, Unity, Unreal Engine, 3D printer proficiency, ANSYS Workbench, embedded systems development, design for manufacturability (DFM), LabVIEW, git version control
- Coding Languages MATLAB & Simulink, C, C++, Python, Swift, Arduino, R, HTML
- Al Experience LLM, RAG, Langchain, OpenAl API, Deep Reinforcement Learning, Scikit-learn, TensorFlow, PyTorch
- Robotics Proficiency Universal Robotics (UR) Lineup, Kinova Gen3 Lite, TurtleBot, ROS, Gazebo

Education

Florida Atlantic University

- BS in Mechanical Engineering with a Minor in Computer Science Innovation Leadership Honors Program (ILHP)
- MS in Artificial Intelligence Big Data Analytics Certificate
- Pursuing a PhD in Computer Science